- 嘻哈帝国 前情提要 - 我们才是帝国娱乐最强的一对
- Previously on Empire... - We're Empire's original power couple.
而不是安德鲁和那个无脑妹
Not Andre and that bobblehead.
我会报复他们俩
I'm gonna get back at the both of 'em.
- 冷静点 - 泽维尔拿我的主意抢了功劳
- Relax. - Xavier took credit for my idea.
让我教你一点报复别人的招数吧
I'll teach you a little something about true payback.
你会清醒地站上那个舞台
You gonna get your ass on that stage, clean and sober.
我需要我的药片
I just need my pills.
我一定要去表演 你懂的
Just got to get to the show, you know that.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
你要去戒毒所了 好吗
And you're going to rehab, okay?
什么
What?
安吉洛酒后驾车掉进湖里
Angelo drunk-drove into a lake,
他自己逃生了 却让车中的女孩淹死了
saving himself while leaving a poor innocent girl to drown.
什么
What?
你先遵从公司高层的指示
You respect the hierarchy.
我在背后操作 直到时机成熟
I pull the strings here until it's time.
什么时机
Time for what?
杀死我爸的时机
Time to kill my father.
专辑In Control和The Chronic是传奇制作人Marley Marl和Dr. Dre的代表作 在嘻哈音乐界具有里程碑式的地位
就像Marley Marl的 控制 和
While Marley gave you In Control
专辑In Control和The Chronic是传奇制作人Marley Marl和Dr. Dre的代表作 在嘻哈音乐界具有里程碑式的地位
Dr.Dre的 慢性 一样
and Dre gave you The Chronic,
专辑In Control和The Chronic是传奇制作人Marley Marl和Dr. Dre的代表作 在嘻哈音乐界具有里程碑式的地位
我将带给你们又一张传奇性的专辑 地狱之火
I give you Inferno.
翻译 rebecca 伦 阿哔 老王 校对 豆腐君
后期 豆腐君 压制 小明
虽说你说过场面会很劲爆 这也太劲爆了吧
You said you was gonna bring the heat, but damn!
也是时候了
Well, it's about time.
去年 我受到来自各方的攻击
For the last year, I've been attacked from all sides.
帮派 FBI
Gangsters, feds,
甚至家里人
even family.
说曹操 曹操就到
Yeah, speaking of which...
不错啊 贾马尔还在戒毒所
Nice of you to announce
你就在这儿公布你那小专辑了
your little project while Jamal's still in rehab.
看来你还是觉得他对你有威胁
It must be because you're still threatened by him.
我都忘了他会做音乐呢
I forgot he was even doing music.
你应该先跟我说一声的 卢修斯
You should have given me the heads-up, Lucious.
按理说 我们都是联合首席执行官
Theoretically, we are co-CEO.
按理说 你还打算一直不理我呢
Theoretically, you weren't talking to me.
姐现在不就理你了吗
Well, I'm speaking to you now.
你要跟你歌迷说
You gonna tell your fans that
你要退居二线做你的专辑了
you are stepping down to work on your project,
让我做首席执行官
leaving me sole CEO of Empire.
算是弥补你试图告密搞垮安吉洛的行为
That's for dry snitching, trying to destroy Angelo.
如果你想和我玩的话 咱们可以玩玩
Yeah, you play with me if you want to.
不 我不玩 我直接开战
No, I don't play. I war.
你想和我开战吗 酷琦
You want war, Cookie?
那就开战吧
Fire a shot.
你等着吧
Get ready.
雷米 玛: 混过街头的纽约MC 目前仅有的5位拥有冠单的女说唱歌手之一
前不久刚出狱 和麻辣鸡Nicki Minaj最近一直在撕逼
剧中Cookie扮演者Taraji在这场撕逼战中公开支持Remy Ma
擦 连雷米 玛都请来了
Damn, Remy Ma.
我跟卢修斯说好了
I already talked to Lucious
要给提安娜做一首她自己的歌
about Tiana doing one of her tracks.
在没跟我商量的前提下
Before you talked to me?
别担心 你会在专辑里拥有自己的歌的
You're gonna get your own track on the album, don't worry.
屌炸天的雷米 玛
The incredible Remy Ma.
天啊 真是太赞了
Damn, girl, amazing.
还有我的兄弟 布里克
And my man, Brikk!
掌声送给他们
Give it up for them.
好了 如你们所知
Now, as y'all know,
我是在费城街头的枪火中成长的
I was forged in the fires of Philadelphia streets.
那些经历让我创作出
And I took that energy and I turned it
一张又一张的专辑
into one album, into another platinum-selling album,
一张又一张的白金唱片
into another platinum-selling album.
而现在 凭着 地狱之火 这张专辑
And now, with Inferno,
我将重回嘻哈世界的巅峰
I retake my rightful place at the top of hip-hop,
- 我的地盘的巅峰 - 那是谁
- at the top of my game. - Who is that?
再创帝国娱乐的巅峰
At the top of the Empire!
发生什么事了
What's going on?
快看看她是谁
Yo, man, check her out.
大家好啊
Hello, everybody!
这是卢修斯最亲爱的妈妈
This is Lucious Lyon's dear mama.
莉亚 沃克
Leah Walker.
- 莉亚 沃克 - 她不是死了吗
- Leah Walker? - Didn't she die?
她在后台 对自己的儿子在这儿
And she was so excited backstage to watch her baby boy
说着自己的成就 感到很激动
out here, talking about all his fabulousness.
她只想到这个舞台上
She just want to come out
跟你们打声招呼 你说吧 妈妈
here and tell y'all hey. Go ahead, mama.
嗨
Hi.
按照 Boom Boom Boom Boom 的MV 她不是自杀了吗
Didn't she commit suicide in the "Boom Boom" Video?
我是莉亚
I'm Leah.
还不快去解围 周
Yo, get out there, Cho!
我是德怀特的
I'm Dwight's...
嘿 各位
Hey, everybody.
你们已经有了宣传资料了
You guys have your press packets.
卢修斯马上要去
Lucious is on his way to
录音室开始制作 地狱之火 了
the studio right now to start work on Inferno.
与此同时
In the meantime,
你们可以在帝国极度流上获取专辑的最新动态 谢谢各位
please check for updates on Empire XStream. Thanks, guys.
你是骗子
You a liar!
她不是死了吗
I thought she was dead!
这一战开得如何
How was that for a shot?
是不是正中要害
Hit any vital organs?
作为联合首席执行官 她知道她是在破坏自己的公司吧
I mean, as co-CEO, she knows she's sabotaging her own company.
或许她已经发泄完了
Well, maybe she's got it out of her system.
酷琦不是这样的人 如果她想要开战
Nah, not Cookie. And if she want war,
我也奉陪到底
I'm gonna give it to her.
好吧 那待会见
All right, I'll see you in a bit,
- 我要去上厕所 - 去吧
- I'm gonna hit the head. - Yeah.
我为内莎定下了极度流的明日之星秀
I got Nessa booked for the XStream Next Up Showcase.
那会成为她的第一个单人演出
It'll be her first solo set.
我很喜欢 做得好 小泽
I love it. Good stuff, X.
谢谢
Thank you.
做得好
Good stuff?
这毫无道理可言 哈基姆和提安娜的专辑都发布得
That makes zero sense. Both Hakeem and Tiana have albums dropping
- 比内莎早 - 确实 不过我是你老板
- before Nessa. - Yeah, but I'm your boss.
安德鲁是我老板 所以你想想吧
Andre is mine, so just do the math.
要这么说
Here's some math.
我在董事会里的表决权可和安德鲁一样大
I have as many voting shares on the board as Andre.
董事会可没有参与到
Well, the board is not involved
公司的日常运作中啊 哈基姆
in the day to day of the company, Hakeem.
酷琦想要提安娜上 你就得让她上
Cookie wants Tiana, so that's what she's gonna get.
老爸
Pop.
现在
So...
来投票表决是让
vote on the table is whether
内莎还是提安娜上台演出
to feature Nessa or Tiana at the showcase.
你是固执还是傻
Yo, are you hardheaded or stupid?
老妈早就定下了
Mom already approved.
你妈定下了谁
Your mom approved who?
提安娜
Tiana.
那就这样决定了
Then it's settled.
让内莎上场
It's Nessa that gets the showcase.
老爸 等等 你不能这么做
Dad, wait, you can't be doing this.
就这么决定了
End of story.
会议结束
We're done here.
- 嘿 贝基 听着 - 你不用说什么抱歉了
- Hey, Becky, listen. - You can save your sorrys,
泽维尔 我不想听
Xavier, I don't want them.
呵呵 你再跟刚才那样在老板们面前顶撞我
No, you come at me in front of the bosses like that again,
我就把你炒了
I will fire you.
这抱歉听着怎么样
How's that sorry for you?
好了 我一抵达波士顿就打给你
All right, so I'm-a hit you when I land in Boston.
你一定要去吗
You really have to go, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
但愿这个杰斯能够有种
I hope this Jayce plays ball.
他们手上有全部的文件了 是吧
I mean, they got all the files, right?
包括那份他们
Including the citation
在我酒驾时截住我的引证
from when they pulled me over for that DUI.
仅那份文件不足以证明事发时我也在
That alone doesn't place me anywhere near that lake
卡拉淹死的湖附近
where Carla drowned.
卡拉
Carla.
你知道吗
You know what?
在没看见那份文件之前
I couldn't even remember her name
我甚至都想不起她的名字
till I saw it in that file.
我只是那晚在派对上遇见她而已
I mean, I just met the girl at that party that night.
那时
It was...
她看上去很不错
She seemed like she was nice.
那杰斯呢
And Jayce?
杰斯 我也不太了解他
Jayce, I didn't know him that well, either.
我们一起上小学
I mean, went to grade school together.
他因为过失杀人坐了六年牢
He ended up doing six years for involuntary manslaughter.
那次拘捕记录已经封存了 但
The arrest records are sealed, but...
学校里没有人再得到他的消息
...nobody from school ever heard from him,
所以要是我能让他
so if I could just get him
为我做证 那
to make a statement, then...
不用担心我
You know what, don't worry about me.
贾马尔已经很让你担心了
You got a lot on your plate with Jamal.
你今天去探视贾马尔吗
You see your boy today, huh?
要见到儿子了 开心吗
You excited to see Jamal?
自从我让他进戒毒所后 这是我第一次见他
It's the first time since I put him in rehab.
没错
That's right.
我很害怕 安吉洛 我只是
I'm so scared, Angelo. I just...
想要我那个健康 头脑清醒 坚强的儿子回来
I want my baby back, healthy, sober and strong.
我知道
I know.
会的
You will.
你只要相信他就好
Hey, just believe in him.
好吗
All right?
- 好 - 你看上很美
- Okay. - You look good.
谢谢
Thank you.
下午好
Good afternoon.
我是卡茨医生 贾马尔的治疗师
I'm Dr. Katz. I'm Jamal's therapist.
贾马尔怎么样
How's Jamal doing?
让他自己跟你说吧
We'll wait for him to tell you.
打扰下 你们这有音响系统吗
Excuse me, do you have a sound system in here?
我想让我哥听听我最近做的一些新歌
I want my brother to hear some new stuff I've been working on.
恐怕你得再等三个星期直到
I'm afraid you'll have to wait another three weeks until...
晴天康复中心不信音乐疗法那一套
Sunny Day Recovery Center doesn't believe in music.
这是这个难民营的众多蠢规则之一
Just one of the many stupid rules at this dire refugee camp.
托莉 这是一个私人家庭会议
Tory, this is a private family session.
托莉 阿什
Yo, Tory Ash.
哈基姆 里昂
Yo, Hakeem Lyon.
还有安德鲁
Oh, and Andre.
以及里昂家女王本人
And the mama bear Lyon herself.
近来如何 酷琦
What's up, Cookie?
- 托莉 - 放松点 乡巴佬
- Tory. - Relax, cornball.
我就是打声招呼
I'm just saying hello.
就贾马尔跟我说的情况看
From what Jamal's told me,
我很惊讶你们里昂家族的小子居然没都进戒毒所
I'm surprised all your little Lyon cubs aren't in rehab.
别惹我 小姑娘 今天老娘没心情
Don't try me, little girl, not today.
- 省省吧 - 哦 酷琦 我可以惹你
- Please. - Oh, Cookie, I could try you,
不过我还是等卢修斯来了再去惹他吧
but I think I'd rather wait and try Lucious instead.
嗯 你是该干这种找死的事
Oh, yeah, you should do that, 'cause you'll stay alive.
我已经告诉你他不会来了
I already told you he's not coming.
想必你们都见到了我酷炫狂拽的好基友 托莉
I see y'all met my crazy-ass friend, Tory.
- 好运 - 谢谢
- Good luck. - Thank you.
- 嗨 妈 - 贾马尔
- Hey, Ma. - Jamal.
- 你看起来气色不错 - 谢了 妈
- You look good. - Thanks, Mom.
- 好久不见 哥们 - 好久不见
- What's up, bro? - What's up, brother?
- 好久不见 德鲁 - 挺吊呀 特洛伊阿什
- What's up, Dre? - Damn. Tory Ash.
自从她在芬威公园全裸上台
The whole world is still wondering what happened to her
全世界都想知道她究竟遭遇了什么
ever since she stripped butt naked onstage at Fenway Park.
放尊敬点 哈基姆 那是个染病的女子
Show some respect, Hakeem. The woman has an illness.
呵呵 你对这种病肯定挺了解
Yeah, you would know a lot about that,
- 是不 - 闭嘴 小子
- wouldn't you? - Shut up, boy.
是呀 她曾经是一个巨星 而且璀璨动人
Yeah, she was a big star. I mean, brilliant, too.
- 是 - 但是海洛因把她从云端
- Yeah. - That heroin knocked her ass
拽了下来
right out the sky.
她在芬威的那场演出简直堪称悲剧
She had that meltdown at Fenway.
她不是被发现昏迷在一家破烂的小旅馆里吗
Didn't they find her in a coma at some dingy motel?
里昂女士 我不得不提醒你 别散布
Mrs. Lyon, I have to ask you not to indulge in gossip
关于其他房客的流言
about other the residents.
抱歉
Sorry.
现在 我们是要等一下里昂先生 还是
Now, should we wait for Mr. Lyon, or...?
像贾马尔说的 他父亲不会来了
like Jamal said, his father ain't coming.
他爸爸怎么了
His father is what?
- 我儿子怎么样了 - 爸
- How's my boy? - Dad.
看看你
Look at you,
神清气爽
all bright-eyed and strong
蓄势待发
and ready for the world.
我宝贝儿子是怎么戒掉拜他妈妈所赐的
How's my boy doing recovering from those addictive drugs
毒瘾的
his mama got him hooked on?
卢修斯 你在这儿站着 就不能给这个家盼点儿好吗
Lucious, if you gonna be here, can you be here for the family?
听到你说这种话也是很讽刺
That's rich, coming from you.
我相信贾马尔非常开心看到家庭团聚
I'm sure Jamal is happy that his whole family is here.
贾马尔
Jamal,
你想告诉他们你怎么想的吗
do you want to tell them what's on your mind
- 在你戒掉毒瘾的过程中 - 好的
- at the halfway point? - Sure.
嗯
Um, well...
第一周我简直生不如死
...first week was absolute hell.
再不想经历毒瘾发作的感觉了
I don't ever want to go through withdrawal again.
我们知道你不会重蹈覆辙的 兄弟
And we know you won't, bro.
是啊 如果你能保持
Yeah, if you stay clean.
如果是什么意思
What do you mean, "If"?
他已经戒毒了
He is clean.
- 对吧 贾马尔 - 百分之百戒毒了
- Right, Jamal? - Completely clean.
你知道 这是
You know, that's...
这就是为什么我想回家
that's why I want to go home.
- 什么 - 我要回家
- What? - I need to go home.
我要回家 有一个旋律一直盘旋在我的脑海中
I got this... this melody that's in my head.
在我于此的每分每秒都催绷着我的神经
It's been pushing me the entire time that I've been here,
我需要在我忘记这个旋律之前
and I need to get to the
赶去录音室 把这首歌做出来
studio and I need to lay it down before I lose it.
我需要在我忘记这个旋律之前
and I need to get to the
赶去录音室 把这首歌做出来
studio and I need to lay it down before I lose it.
所以 你的身体恢复了 我很高兴
So, your body is healed... I get that...
但是你还得住在这 直到这个疗程结束
but you need to stay and finish this program.
妈 要我完成这个疗程
Okay, Ma, I need to finish the program.
就跟要我把你之前倒掉的药磕掉一样
I also need to finish the pills in the drain.
对不起妈 我不该那么说
I'm sorry, Ma, that was messed up.
这么说对你并不公平 对不起
That wasn't fair to you, I'm sorry.
我给你那些药 是因为我看到我的儿子痛不欲生 贾马尔
I gave you those pills because I saw you were in pain, Jamal.
别 说实话
No, tell the truth.
你给他这些药是因为你需要他
You gave him those pills because you needed him
在那场演唱会上表演
to perform at that event.
你也很矛盾 因为你不得不在
You also was conflicted because you had to choose
你的儿子和你的男朋友
between the needs of your boyfriend
的需求之间抉择
or the needs of your son.
- 你不知道他对安吉洛做了什么 - 我对安吉洛做了什么
- You don't know what he did to Angelo. - What I did to Angelo...
- 里昂先生 里昂太太 - 你能他妈的闭嘴吗
- Mr. And Mrs. Lyon... -  Would you shut the hell up?
我对安吉洛做的远不及
It's not half as bad as
你对公司和帝国娱乐这块招牌所造成的影响恶劣
what you did to Empire and to Empire's name.
贾马尔和我都厌倦了为家族名声洗白
Jamal and I are sick and tired of cleaning up the family name.
你都已经不应该还
It's a name you're not even supposed to have
- 冠以这个姓氏 - 是啊 因为你建立了一切
- in the first place. - Oh, right, cause you built everything...
- 你名字里就不该带着里昂 - 那是呀 你建立的这一切
- First or last name. - You built everything...
嘿 伙计
Hey, what's up, papa.
给我一个热狗
Let me get one of them dirty dogs.
这些都是犹太净食 对吧
They're Kosher, right?
给您
There you go.
谢谢
Gracias.
没啥东西比得上一个好吃的热狗
Ain't nothing like a good pimp steak.
劳驾给我点餐巾纸好吗
Hand me a couple napkins, will you?
谢谢
Thank you.
你确信
And you're sure
FBI正在调查弗兰克 盖哲思的谋杀案
it's about Frank Gathers' murder?
我的意思是 这只是斯威特沃特探员的一家之言
I mean, so says Agent Sweetwater.
在我看来
And the way I figure it,
有人获得了轻松出狱的机会
somebody scored a "Get out of jail free" Card.
然后塔里克安排他去大陪审团作证
And Tariq got him lined up to testify to a grand jury
是你下令杀了弗兰克 盖哲思
that you're the one who ordered the hit on Gathers.
所以 我是说你想想
I mean, so you tell me, I mean,
有谁可能是这个告密者呢
d-does anybody come to mind?
盖 他远在隆波克（加州城市）
Well, Guy, he's back at Lompoc.
而米奇在泽西中了枪
And Mikey caught a bullet up in Jersey,
所以
so...
嫌疑人就只剩下了
that leaves
一个人 鲍比 金
one man, Bobby King,
又称 告密的杂种
A.K.A. Rat bastard.
- 是巴巴（鲍比的昵称） - 就是巴巴
- Bam-Bam. - Bam-Bam.
想来我还给了他不少钱
And to think I spent
来医治她女儿的白血病
a bunch of money on his daughter's leukemia bills,
然而她还是死了
and she still died.
我知道了这个名字
I got the name.
我会找到巴巴的藏身之所的
I'll find out where Bam-Bam's hiding.
听着 瑟斯第
Look, Thirst?
关于我妈妈出现在新闻上的事
You know, this business about my mama
你懂的
and the press, you know...
要特别留意
keep an eye on it.
好的 没问题
Yeah, it's not a problem.
我会好好看着她
I'll keep her in my sights.
巴巴
Bam-Bam.
看起来不错 他们终于正确地把我的名字拼出来了
Looking good, and they finally spelled my name right.
看起来有人正在平步青云啊
Looks like somebody's moving up in the world.
祝贺 老兄
Congratulations, brother.
谢谢
Thanks.
你听说了我帮内莎搞定的好事了吗
You hear about what I hooked up for Nessa?
嗯 听说了 明日之星秀
Yeah, the, uh, Next Up Showcase.
这不错
It's good.
她应得的
She deserves it.
这只是个垫脚石 老兄
Well, stepping stones, my friend.
计划的第一阶段
Phase one of the plan.
说到这个计划
Speaking of the plan,
你知道的
you know...
地狱之火 估计会屌得很
Inferno 'bout to be a monster.
卢修斯会比以往更加强大
Lucious is about to be bigger than ever.
就目前而言 你无法从他那偷走帝国娱乐
There's no way you're stealing Empire from him right now.
我没有说我要从他那偷走帝国娱乐
I didn't say I was gonna steal it from him.
我是说 我要杀了他
I said I'm gonna kill him.
当卢修斯忙着制作 地狱之火 我们就私下操作
While Lucious is making Inferno, we'll be making moves,
招兵买马
mounting an army.
兵马
An army?
对的
That's right.
你是指我的人
You mean my guys?
我想说他们是我们的人 肖恩
I'd like to think of them as our guys, Shine.
欢迎来到帝国娱乐
Welcome to the Empire.
我写了一份解释声明
I've got a statement you can read explaining
你可以借此解释你只是在保护你母亲的隐私
you were just protecting the privacy of your mother.
我几时怕过这些了
When have you ever known me not to come off the dome?
我确信你们有很多的问题
I'm sure you got a bunch of questions,
所以我们干脆打开天窗说亮话
so why don't we just push to the punch?
你们想问我的母亲 对吧
You want to ask about my mother, right?
是的
Yes, we do.
好 但是这是一个非常隐私的事情
Well, that's a very private
它的处理自然也是私密的
matter and it's being handled privately.
好 但是这是一个非常隐私的事情
Well, that's a very private
它的处理自然也是私密的
matter and it's being handled privately.
但我确实有一个问题想问你们
But what I do have is a question for you.
你们准备选谁当市长
Who are you voting for for mayor?
因为我知道我支持约翰 米克斯
Because I know I'm endorsing John Meeks.
你们难道不觉得纽约是时候
Don't you think it's time
需要一个像约翰 米克斯这样极富领导素质
that New York had a mayor that had the leadership qualities
与领导才干的市长吗
and the integrity of someone like John Meeks?
你们知道 他可不像安吉洛 杜布瓦
You see, he's not a criminal,
那样是个罪犯
like Angelo Dubois.
他从来没有任一位女士溺死于车中
He would never leave a woman to drown in a car
只因为他想逃避酒驾的罪名
because he was trying to avoid a DUI.
实际上 为了缅怀那个很多年前去世了的年轻女子
In fact, in honor of that young woman who died so many years ago,
我将要提供三十万美金的奖励
I'm going to offer a $300,000 cash reward
给任何一个掌握相关信息
for anyone that has any information
可以使嫌犯先生定罪的人
that can lead to the conviction of Mr. "Dubious" Dubois.
你在做什么
What are you working on?
有东西在我的脑海中和灵感撞了个满怀
Oh, something that was in my head.
不过 这里的声效还真是很棒啊
Yo, the acoustics here are crazy, though.
我知道 挺棒的 是吧
I know. It's kind of amazing, right?
在我来这之前
Before I came in here, man, just...
我有音乐 激情
the music, the passion, just...
没人能追得上我
...couldn't nobody catch me.
谁也不能对我指手画脚
And they couldn't tell me nothing.
我知道
I know, right?
那种火一般的激情 好像所有的东西都在高压下迸发
That fire, it's like everything was high pressure.
我以为我在飞翔
I felt like I was flying.
我以为我可以依靠自己撬动世界
I felt like I could propel myself off the Earth
只要我想
if I wanted to.
哦 天啊 我真怀念那种感觉
Oh, God, I miss that so much.
那是世界顶级之嗨
It's the best high in the world.
说实话 我也很怀念那种感觉
I can't lie, I miss it, too.
总是在天马行空
Was always flying.
那我们为什么不去重拾那种激情呢
So why don't we go get it?
欢迎来到 明日之星秀
Welcome to the Next Up Showcase,
表演嘉宾 帝国娱乐当红新秀 内莎 帕克
featuring Empire's hot new artist, Nessa Parker!
你居然来了
Suprised to see you here.
你是想要来领那份悬赏吗
What you want to collect on that reward?
你有什么关于杀人狂先生的信息给我吗
You got some info for me about Mr. Manslaughter?
你简直是青楼名媛 你天天把安吉洛的名字
You're such a fame whore. You got to keep Angelo's name
挂在嘴边 就是为了显示你没过气
on your mouth just to stay relevant?
是的 这就为什么这地方的标志上还挂着我的肖像
Yeah, that's why it's my face still on the logo in this place.
把内莎的麦克风重新接上 现在
Get Nessa's mic back on now!
别 内莎是专业的 她能搞定
Don't. Nessa's a pro. She can handle it.
老兄 现在把你手给我松开
Man, get your hands off me.
你能不能换点新花样玩儿
Might wanna start making some plays out of a new playbook.
这些把戏真是老套又无聊
All this is getting very old and very boring.
提安娜比内莎的咖位更大 笨蛋
Tiana is a bigger star than Nessa, boo-boo.
你应该感谢我为你这个傻逼演唱会
You ought to be thanking me for bringing more eyeballs
- 吸引了这么多眼球 - 你说啥
- to your wack-ass concert. - What'd you say?
我可是引爆了这个场子 把你的助听器开大点声吧
I got it lit in here. Turn up your hearing aid.
她的麦能用了 看着吧
Her mic's back on. Now watch this.
嘿 敬帝国娱乐
Yeah, to the Empire!
喔噢 太棒了 宝贝
Yes, baby, yes!
婊砸 想搞我是没用的
Bitch, you tried it.
鉴于我是个淑女 这一次就不揍你了
I'm a lady, so I'm not gonna beat your ass this time.
就冲着你上回抢了我的时装秀 我才应该痛打你一顿
I should've beat your ass for stealing that fashion show,
老还脏的丑婊子
you old dusty skank.
臭婊子 你他妈
Bitch, who do you think you...
知不知道你在跟谁说话
-...talking to?!
靠边站 让她们打
Nah, back up! Let them fight!
哇 这是怎么了
That's what's up, yeah!
狗娘养的
Bitch!
哇 看看你都做了什么
Uh-uh! Look what you did.
你让人家姑娘在全世界面前
Now you got that girl's ass beat
- 掐起来了 - 你以为我不敢揍你
- in front of the whole world. - You don't know me!
滚回去
Stay in your place!
死婊子
Bitch!
你个贱逼
Cheap-ass ho!
怎么 你想怎么着
What? What you gonna do about it?
打死她个婊子 内莎
Drag that bitch, Nessa!
喂
Hello?
肖恩 哈基姆
Shine! Hakeem!
不 不 让她们打 让她们打个爽
Nah, nah! Let them fight! Let them fight!
什么 什么 什么时候的事
Wait, wait, when did this happen?
- 拜托 伙计 快闪开 - 揍死你
- Come on, man, get out the way! - Beat your ass!
放开我
Let me go!
戒毒所刚刚查房说
Well, they did a bed check at the rehab.
贾马尔不见了
Jamal's not in his bed.
内莎 冷静点内莎
Nessa! Nessa, calm down!
- 够了 够了 - 让她们打
- Stop! Stop! - That's what's up!
我们去找找德里克那个混蛋
Let's go see D-Major and his punk ass.
我们得去找他 卢修斯
We got to find him, Lucious.
噢 哥们你真是个天才
Yeah, man, you're a genius, man.
我还想多加一点低音进去 嘿 卢修斯
I want to add a little bit more bass. Hey, Lucious,
噢 哥们你真是个天才
Yeah, man, you're a genius, man.
我还想多加一点低音进去 嘿 卢修斯
I want to add a little bit more bass. Hey, Lucious,
正好你在这 你来听听这首
I'm glad you're here. I need your ear
就是那首  搞什么鬼
on this one. You know the thing... What the hell?
放开我
Get off me.
给我 放手
Get... off...
我儿子在哪 德里克
Where's my son, D?
你儿子在戒毒所 酷琦
Your son is in rehab, Cookie.
不 他不在 而我知道
No, he left rehab, and I know
你一直都给他供毒
you've been supplying him with his drugs.
要是我儿子因为过量吸毒出了什么事 你也得死
If my son ends up O.D.'ing, your ass is dead.
你在说什么呢 酷琦
What are you talking about, Cookie?
你怎么能还给他毒品呢
How you helping him by giving him drugs?
他很痛苦 你知道的
He's in pain, and you know that.
我做不到看着他痛苦却什么也不做
I couldn't just stand there and watch him suffer like that.
所以你就给他毒品 妈的 我真是受够了
So you give him drugs. Man, I'm sick of this.
卢修斯 我发誓我什么也没做
Lucious, I wouldn't do nothing, man, I swear.
酷琦我找到他了 你看
Cookie, I found him! Look!
有人在网上发了一个他和托莉 阿什的视频
Somebody posted a video on Snapchat of him and Tory Ash.
他们在一个脏乱的街区
They over in some dirty-ass neighborhood.
或者是什么毒窝里
Or some crack house.
他妈给我闭嘴
Shut your ass up!
我知道在哪 滚开
I know where that is. Move!
为什么沃克夫人也在车上
Why is Mrs. Walker in the backseat?
卢修斯要我看着她
Lucious wants me to keep an eye on her
直到我给她找到个保姆
until I can find her a babysitter.
那你再给我解释一下 怎么
So explain to me again how,
贝基 和我一起跑一趟 这句话
"Becky come on this run with me,"
就能理解成是你要帮我把泽维尔
is gonna translate into you helping me out
那个人渣除掉
with that scumbag Xavier?
我知道怎么对付小人
I know how to handle scumbags.
好的 放轻松点 神奇奶奶 我们知道你可以
All right, take it easy, Granny Gru. We know you do.
瑟斯第 我们在这是干嘛呢
Thirsty, what are we doing?
我们要帮卢修斯一个朋友的忙 坐好了
We're just doing a favor for a friend of Lucious. Sit tight.
她要坐进来了吗
She coming in here?
贝基 拜托 友好一点
Becky, please, be nice.
嗯哼
Mm-mm.
是你朋友吗
Is that your friend?
我不认识她
I don't know her.
兄弟 这给你
Here you go, man.
- 干得不错 - 谢谢您 先生
- Good looking out. - Thank you, sir.
还好吗 格雷琴女士
How you doing, Miss Gretchen?
噢 我迫不及待要见到我的宝贝了
Oh, I can hardly wait to see my Bam-Bam.
他真是个好儿子
He's such a good son.
他要把我送到亚利桑那州的一家养老院
He's moving me to a nursing home in Arizona.
嗯没错 他真的很棒
That's good. Oh, he's a good boy.
好了
All right.
我的德怀特当初就把我关在一家养老院
My Dwight had me locked up in one of those homes
关了好几百年
for over a hundred years.
那些地方很邪恶
Those places are evil.
好了 好了
Okay, okay...
我懂你为什么没有让我出去
I know damn well you ain't got me
帮你绑架这些老太太了
out here helping you kidnap these old ladies.
我可不做这种事
I am not doing a bid for this.
没有 她开玩笑的 别紧张
No, she just kidding, Gran. Just relax.
我像是要绑架你们吗
Do I look like a kidnapper to you?
- 像 - 真是谢谢你了好吗 我是个律师
- Yes. - I'm a lawyer, thank you very much.
我是在努力指导你什么才叫
All right? And I'm trying to instruct you on the virtues
看准时机再出手
of the perfectly-timed execution.
为此你需要耐心 小蚂蚱
For that, you need patience, Grasshopper.
好的 系好安全带 老姑娘们
All right, buckle up, golden girls.
你们坐在后面还好吗 需要开暖气吗
You good back there? You need the heat on?
看路
Watch the road!
贾马尔在哪 泰里
Where's Jamal, Tyree?
贾马尔 我没见过他
Jamal? I ain't seen him.
我告诉你 今晚你可不想跟我对着干
Look, you don't want no trouble with me tonight.
不然我拆了这烂录音室
I will tear this raggedy-ass studio down.
任何她没毁掉的东西 我会
And whatever she doesn't destroy, I will.
- 这是怎么了 卢修斯 - 怎么了 回答我的问题
- What's up, Lucious? - What's up?! Answer the question!
喂 喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey!
- 我没有在开玩笑 - 他在楼上 第一录音室
- Yeah, this ain't a joke. - He's upstairs, studio one.
你在这做什么 贾马尔
What you doing, Jamal?
你妈找你找得都快得心脏病了
Your mother almost had a heart attack looking for you.
你们以为呢 我在录一首歌
What y'all think? I'm recording a song.
听着 我会让韦伯在这儿搜一圈
Look, I'm-a have Webb run through this whole place.
只要我们发现一丝丝毒品的痕迹
We find one speck of drugs...
- 没错 - 老天呐
- That's right. - Oh, my God.
爸 我说过我已经完全戒掉了 我现在也是如此
Dad, I said that I am sober and clean, and I am.
那你为什么离开戒毒所了呢
Then why did you leave rehab?
听着 现在需要做的
Listen, what needs to happen
就是让我们完成这首歌的录制
right now is we need to finish this song,
听着 现在需要做的
Listen, what needs to happen
就是让我们完成这首歌的录制
right now is we need to finish this song,
所以你们就先
so y'all need to just...
你现在应该做的就是闭嘴
What you need to do is shut up.
- 噢 天呐 - 臭婊子
- Oh, Lord... - Bitch!
- 妈 妈 你听我 - 你就是
- You know what... Ma, Ma! - What you need
- 欠打 - 妈 别这样
- is your ass beat! - Mom, please.
- 你不想这样的 - 求你了 求你了 别这样
- You don't want none of this. - Please, please. No.
- 是啊 - 她不想的 她真的不想的
- Yeah. - She don't. She really don't.
- 咱们是不是得进入警戒状态 - 停 求你们了 爸 妈
- Why do have to go to DEFCON... - Please, stop. Ma, Dad!
妈 别说了
Mom, stop.
我现在想待的地方
Where I'm supposed to be
以及我想要做音乐的地方 就是这儿
and doing what I'm supposed to be doing is right here.
这里就是我的戒毒所
This is my rehab.
好吗
Come on.
好 完成你的录制
Okay, finish your song.
谢谢你 爸爸
Thank you, Dad.
我很抱歉 走吧
I'm sorry. Come on.
你能相信我的 妈妈 相信我
You can trust me, Ma. Come on.
走吧 酷琦
Come on, Cook.
我在外面等你 录完了带你回家
I'll be out here to take you home when you're done.
抱歉各位
Sorry, y'all.
上菜啦
Order up.
妈妈
Mama?
Mama!
嘿 巴巴 先别走
Hey, Bam, don't leave just yet.
卢修斯 你听我解释
L, man, let me explain.
不 你不用解释
No, you don't speak.
我来说
I speak.
你看 我知道发生了什么事 巴巴
You see, I understand how things happen, Bam.
我和FBI都知道 每个人都有他的弱点
Me and the Feds both know that every man has his weakness.
而你的弱点 就是外面那个亲切
And in your case, it's that sweet,
又慈祥 养育你长大
loving woman out there that raised you
并在你蹲监狱的时候抚养你女儿的女人
and then raised your little girl when you got locked up.
但是在咱们被关在一起的时候
But when you and I were locked up,
我承诺过要照顾她们
I made a promise to take care of them.
我也尽我所能去帮助你的女儿
And I did everything I could to help your little girl,
就算她已经过世
but now that she's gone...
我始终坚守诺言 照顾你的妈妈
...I still kept my word and took care your mama.
那么等你站在大陪审团面前的时候
The same way you're gonna remember your P's and Q's
你也应该要记得你的承诺
when you get in front of that grand jury.
很好 拿去吧
All right. Here you go.
我们把巴巴妈妈平安送回家
We got Bam-Bam's mother home safe and sound.
神奇奶奶也睡着了 感谢上帝
Granny Gru has gone night-night, thank God.
我刚去电台送了个爱心包裹
And I just dropped off the care package at WZVX.
任务都完成了
Check, check and check.
怎么了 是我忘了什么吗
What, am I forgetting something?
你忘了我
You forgetting me.
你是认真
Are you ser...
你用这辆破车载着我绕了泽西一圈就办了这么些破事
You got me driving all over Jersey on these dumbass errands.
我们什么时候才来说一下我的问题
When are we gonna talk about my problems though?
好吧 你先跟我说说 大急眼
All right, you know what? Explain it to me, Hot Pocket.
你为什么一直那么紧张那个乡巴佬泽维尔
Why are you still stressing out over that cornball Xavier?
哎呀 你不懂
Yo, you don't get it.
从他进入帝国娱乐以来 他就一直烦我
Ever since he got to Empire, he's been all up in my face
在暗地里使手段 还满口
and doing shady stuff, talking about,
噢 噢 这只是工作 这只是工作
"Oh, oh, it's just business, it's just business."
其实又是一副跟我有私仇的样子
But acting like it's personal with me.
你要知道 第一点
There you go. Lesson one.
没错 那是工作
It's business, of course.
但无论别人怎么告诉你 这种从来都是私仇
But no matter what anybody tells you, it's always personal.
好的 那我要怎么做
Okay, so what I do?
你还能做什么呢
You know what, what more can you do?
额
Yo.
没事的 别紧张姑娘
All right, relax, mama.
这不是给你的
That's not for you.
就让一切顺其自然
Just let the universe work its magic.
好吗
Okay?
老天会挺你的
It's got you.
又是少林和尚的那套扯淡
Type of Shaolin monk bull...
你知道吗 你浪费了我一整天
You know what? You have wasted my entire day.
浪费我的时间
Waste of time.
少林武当
Shaolin Wu-Tang.
所以里昂 卢修斯又赢了
So Lucious Lyon wins again.
你在这案子里的主要证人
You built this case up on one star witness,
巴巴 金 突然拒绝作证了
Bam-Bam King, who suddenly refuses to testify.
是啊 里昂肯定不知道又用什么手段搞定他了
Yeah, Lyon must've got to him somehow.
他杀了弗兰克 盖哲思 我可以证明
He murdered Frank Gathers, and I can prove it.
我需要更多的时间
I just need more time.
探员 到此为止 你的时间已经到了
Agent, your time is up; as of right now,
我需要更多的时间
I just need more time.
探员 到此为止 你的时间已经到了
Agent, your time is up; as of right now,
你不用参与这案子了 因为它结束了
you're off the case, 'cause it's closed.
什么 我还有别的线索啊 长官
What? But I have more leads, sir.
由于你事前隐秘了他是你的半个兄弟的事实
Any evidence against the target is tainted
导致任何关于目标的证据都不足采信
due to your omission of the fact that he is your half-brother.
我会让你带薪休假的
I'm putting you on paid leave.
杜布瓦先生的竞选终于能喘口气了
Mr. Dubois' campaign got a much needed breath of life
杰斯 琼斯出来证实 他已经为20年前的
when Jayce Jones came forward to confirm that he served time
卡拉 米尔斯溺水身亡事件
for the manslaughter death of Carla Mills,
以过失杀人的罪名服过刑了
who drowned in a lake over 20 years ago.
而且最重要的是 事发时
And most important, that Angelo Dubois
安吉洛 杜布瓦根本不在现场
was nowhere near the scene when it happened.
老天爷
God.
老爸使的招好阴
Dad went so low.
你还感到惊讶吗
Are you surprised?
习以为常却依然被刷新三观
Always and never.
怎么了
What?
我长话短说
I'm gonna keep this short...
只讲真话
and real.
你还在吸毒吗
Are you a dope fiend?
听着 我之前是吸毒了 妈
Look, I got caught up, Ma.
我并没有试图逃避这一点
I ain't even trying to run away from that.
但是我敢用我的音乐和所有发誓
But I swear on my music and everything else
我一直努力从中枪事件中恢复过来
that I've been fighting back for since I came back
我 我已经戒毒了
from the bullet, I... I'm done with the pills.
真的
Really.
我的精神太集中了 我甚至不想有任何
I'm so focused. I'm not even trying to have any kind of substance
事情去搅浑它
mess with that.
听你那么说我很高兴 宝贝
I'm happy to hear that, baby.
终于感觉一切都会变得好起来
Finally feels like everything's gonna be all right.
你没事了
You're okay.
安吉洛的事解决了
Angelo's situation is settled.
他已经重回竞选了 所以
He's back on his campaign, so...
是的 他很棒 是吗
Yeah, he's good, right?
以后就知道了
We'll see.
我的意思是 政治就是这样 他们只需要往你身上泼脏水
I mean, it's politics; all they got to do is say it,
你就永远洗不干净
it sticks to you like stink.
卢修斯所做的一切都是为了你
Lucious did all of that just for you.
这是一种扭曲的爱 老兄
That is a twisted kind of love, man.
我知道他在为他的下一步动作做准备
I know he's planning his next move.
现在 在我们开始之前
Now, before we get started,
让我们做一个简短的小决定
let's take care of a short order of business.
泽维尔
Xavier.
你被开除了
You're fired.
- 好吧 我们走 - 哇哦 别这样 兄弟 什么鬼
- All right, let's go. - Whoa, come on, man! What the hell?
让这个作为你们每一个人的反面典型
Let this serve as an example for each and every one of you.
如果我抓住任何人索要回扣
If I catch anybody getting kickbacks,
相信我 下一次的惩罚绝对比开除要惨得多
trust me, the next time you'll get much more than fired.
里昂先生 里昂先生 我从来没有对不起你过 兄弟
Mr. Lyon, Mr. Lyon, I would never do that to you, man.
- 我向上帝发誓 我是无辜的 - 无辜
- I swear to God, I'm innocent on this! - Innocent?
你去跟WZVX电台的节目主管说吧
Tell that to the program director over at WZVX.
你做事不地道 兄弟 不地道
You run a sloppy business, man, sloppy.
别这样 真的 这是一个谎言 贝基
Come on, now, that's a lie! Becky!
贝基 你知道我的 是吧 你了解我
Becky, you know me. All right? You know me.
你要为我做证 拜托
You need to vouch for me. Come on.
我可不知道你 老兄 公事公办
I don't know you, man. It's just business.
公事公办
"Just business"?
再见
Bye.
嗨 老兄 我是无辜的
Yo, I'm innocent, man!
嗨 我可没这么干
Yo, I didn't do this!
放开我
Get off me!
接着滚 别停
Go on out of here.
现在好戏已经结束了
Now that the fireworks are over,
我很确定你们都听说了我要做的新专辑
I'm sure you've all heard my announcement
地狱之火 虽然这个房间里某些人
about Inferno, even though it may have been muffled a bit by
-可能对此不太爽 - 卢修斯 听着
- certain people in this room. - Uh, Lucious, look,
所有这个房间的人
everyone in this room
都很忙 所以如果你能赶紧
is very busy, so if you could go ahead,
结束你要说的 那就太感谢了
and finish what you have to say, thank you.
我就快结束了
I'm getting there.
我们是里昂家族 因此 我们只玩大的
We are Lyons; therefore, we roar.
所以从现在开始 公司的每个员工
So from this point forward, each and every employee
首要任务就是
of this company, their number one priority
确保 地狱之火 的成功制作
is to make sure that Inferno is what it should be.
这是我正在制作的专辑
It's an album I'm producing.
我要帝国娱乐的顶级艺人参与进来
I'm going to have the top artists from Empire on it,
而且我希望我的儿子 贾马尔
and I'm hoping that my son, Jamal,
能不吝赐我一首歌
will bless me with a song.
现在 艺人监理部总监的位置
Now, seeing that the position of head of A&R
空了出来
has recently just opened,
我决定找一个配得上这个位置的人
I decided to fill it with someone that I feel is
来担此重任
worthy of such a position.
由于处于这个位置
And as a result of being in this position,
她承受了很多来自我的痛苦和煎熬
she's come to be under a great deal of anguish and fire
因为她曾经
from me because she's been
是我最大的评论家
my biggest critic, which in turn turned her
这也让她变了我最棒的盟友 她非常忠诚
into my greatest ally, and she's very loyal.
过去我对任命她在这个位置非常犹豫
And I was so hesitant to appoint her in this position
因为我不想
because I didn't want to
让她离开她的第一职责
take her away from her first responsibility,
因为我不想
because I didn't want to
让她离开她的第一职责
take her away from her first responsibility,
也就是做为一个母亲的职责
and that's the job of being a mother.
但她会像过去多年一样帮助我
But she will serve me as she has for years,
作为我的缪斯 点燃我内心的地狱之火
as my muse who has lit an inferno inside of me.
她是这个公司的创始核心
She is the DNA of this company,
我的妻子 阿妮卡 里昂女士
my wife, Mrs. Anika Lyon.
你们的新艺人监理部总监
Your new head of A&R.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝贺
Congrats.
来吧 坐下
Come on. Take your seat.
哈 这位子已经为你备好了
Ha! Nice and warm for you.
嗯 嗯 嗯 这音乐很给力 卢修斯
Mm, mm-mm, that is fire, Lucious.
是的 地狱之火
Yeah, "Inferno."
这个名字很合适
The name fits.
怎么 你想找麻烦吗 酷琦
What, you want some trouble, Cookie?
不 不 我 我不想找麻烦 卢修斯
No, no, I-I don't want no trouble, Lucious.
我只是有些问题 只是这样
I just have some questions, is all.
就像 这里的这张专辑
Like, this-this album right here.
这是你的第一张金唱片
This was your first album to go gold.
现在 我记得在我进监狱之前
Now, I remember working on that six months
我可为此忙活了六个月
before I went to prison.
所以 到底谁是公司的创始核心呢 卢修斯
So, whose DNA is in that, Lucious? Huh?
创始核心 小子 少来了
DNA. Boy, please.
她就是个婊子
Ain't nothing but a hood rat.
好吧
All right.
我们就玩一会
Let's play.
我告诉过你吗
Did I tell you, I watched you on TV
当帝国娱乐的第一张专辑被引入
in that dirty-ass rec room
音乐名人殿堂时 我通过丹伯里的
in Danbury when Empire's first album was inducted
那个肮脏娱乐室里的电视看着你
into the Music Hall of Fame.
谁是你那张专辑的缪斯
Who was your muse for that?
你闹够了没 贱人
You done, bitch?
啊 卢修斯 别靠近我
Huh, Lucious? Don't you come any closer.
把它放下
Put it down.
那时候谁是你这张专辑的缪斯 啊
Who was your muse on that, huh?!
那时候谁是你的缪斯 卢修斯
Who was your muse, Lucious?
噢 你还记得这个吗
Oh, do you remember this one?
我记得
Because I do.
是的 我在监狱里帮你来回传送磁带
Yeah, I sent tapes from the inside
帮你在外面制作这张专辑
back and forth with you while you worked on them out here.
噢 还有这一个
Oh! And this one.
这个是你不再来探望我以后弄的
This is when you stopped coming to visit me.
这张很垃圾
It was weak.
所有的评论家都是这么说的
All the critics said so.
是的 起来
Yeah, get up.
如果没有我 这一切都不会存在
None of this would've existed without me!
这些金唱片 荣誉奖章都不存在
Not those gold records! Not those plaques!
这个录音室也不会存在
Not this studio!
什么都不会存在
None of it!
所以你告诉我 卢修斯
So you tell me, Lucious.
告诉我谁的DNA贯穿了这一切
Tell me whose DNA is running all through it?
嗯
Huh?
谁才是那个身负重任的母亲 卢修斯
Who's the mother with the important job, Lucious?!
你告诉我
You tell me.
我给你生了三个儿字 贱人 三个儿子
I gave you three sons, bitch, three sons!
我还为你流过产
I had a miscarriage.
我在监狱呆了17年 所以你才能建立这个
I went to jail for 17 years so you could build this!
所以你才能建立这个帝国
So you could build this Empire!
是的 跟着我
Yeah, follow me!
我会告诉这儿有谁的DNA
I'll show you whose DNA is in here.
好 现在你完了
Okay, now you die!
你说里昂家族都是用吼的 好 现在让我听你吼两声
You said Lyons roar? Well, let me hear you roar.
是的 我来这儿就是为了制造噪音的
Yeah, I came here to make a lot of noise.
现在你死定了
Now you die!
滚
Go home.
我这只是刚刚开始
I'm just getting started. -
试图抹去我的存在 卢修斯
Trying to erase me, Lucious?
嗯
Huh?
在我为你付出一切之后
After all I done for you.
我为这个家付出了17年
I did 17 years for this family.
你是靠我才建立起这个公司
You built this company on my back.
你现在却想把这给那个贱人
And you just gonna give it to that bitch.
这就是你的计划吗 卢修斯
Is that your plan, Lucious?
嗯
Huh?!
放开我
Let go of me!
停下来
Stop.
嗯 不
Mm-mm.
不
No.
我说过我跟你之间已经完了
I said I was done with you.
我是认真的
I meant that.